RAZAN ABU-DAGEN

IT SYSTEMS ANALYST | DATA ANALYST

Profile

Skilled systems analyst with 4 years of experience in assessing business needs and translating them into relevant solutions. Organized and resultsoriented with top-notch project management and problem-solving skills. Experienced in data modeling and Diagramming on Lucidchart, Draw.io, and Rational Rose. Besides Data visualization tools like Google Colab and Microsoft Power BI.

EXPERIENCE

SYSTEMS ANALYST

Avocode Company

2018 - 2022

- Prepared charts, diagrams, and tables to depict present and proposed systems.
- Formulated and designed computer systems using data modeling, information engineering, and structured analysis.
- Worked with UX and UI personnel to develop interface elements designed to provide ease of use for customers.
- Defined application problems by consulting with clients to evaluate procedures and processes.

TECHNICAL COORDINATOR

Watin Plus Company

2019 - 2020

- · Recommended system revisions and updates using research and problemsolving talents.
- Documented internal processes and procedures to manage post-launch technology effectiveness.
- Managed organizational IT initiatives by collaborating with teammates to optimize infrastructure effectiveness.

DATA ENTRY AUDITOR

Palestinian Ministry of Labor

2018 - 2019

- Transferred written information into databases to maintain consistent, accurate job-hunters records and their details.
- Entered over 700 pieces of Applicant data into the software with 99% accuracy.

1 00966541211988



Razann.255@gmail.com



Al Rawdha St. Abdullah Fouad District, Dammam Saudi Arabia



https://www.linkedin.com/in/raza n-abu-dagen/



Nationality: American

QUALIFICATIONS

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN **COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Al Azhar University, Gaza Palestine 2019 - 2022

DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE &DATABASES

College of Al Azhar Intermediate Studies, Gaza Palestine

2016 - 2018

SKILLS

- In-depth Analysis
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Flexibility
- Interpersonal and Communication Skills
- Computer Skills
- RDMS Development and SQL
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Solution Development
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- · Requirements Gathering
- Programming Languages: Java, C#, .Net, Python

INTERNSHIPS

DATABASE ARCHITECT

Perfecto IT Solution

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019

 Analyzed big Databases into UML Diagrams to improve the software development process.

IT TECHNICIAN

Palestinian Cellular Telecommunications JAWWAL Company Jun 2018 - Jul 2018

• Conducted routine maintenance on servers and systems, keeping networks fullyoperational during peak periods.

TRAINING EXPERIENCE

AI BOOSTING PROGRAM (DATA SCIENCE)

Cognitro AI (New York)

Jan 2021 - Feb 2021

The program aimed to train people interested in the field of AI and Entrepreneurship, to
develop solutions for local market issues formulated by experts. It was in partnership with
MERGE Technology for Sustainable Development, UNDP, and the Swiss Agency for
Development and Cooperation SDC.

DATA SCIENCE WITH PYTHON

Women's Affairs Center

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Applied feature selection algorithms to predict potential outcomes.
- Cleaned and manipulated raw data.
- Created graphs and charts detailing data analysis results.

DATA SCIENCE

Kaggle.com Platform

Jun 2020 - Jul 2020

• Completed training on Kaggle Data Science Platform in the following: (Intro to Machine learning, Intermediate Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Python, Pandas).